AKRITI BANSAL

GRAPHIC DESIGNER

- Bengaluru, IN
- +91 83370 39265
- akritibansal98@gmail.com
- www.behance.net/AkritiB

I'm a visual communicator with 3 years of experience in the Graphic Design industry. With a relentless desire for growth and innovation, I'm well-versed in translating goals to visually expressive assets. I also enjoy exploring interactive and multimedia avenues to push design boundaries.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Mt. Vanda

Sikkim/ Kolkata, IN (Sep 2022 - Present)

Paramahamsi Ganga Ashram

Madhya Pradesh, IN (Jul 2021 - Jul 2022)

Cocoa Bakery

Kolkata, IN (Aug - Sep 2019)

Alliance française du Bengale

Kolkata, IN (Jul - Aug 2019)

MCM Comic Con

London, UK (Oct 2018)

GRAPHIC DESIGNER

- Customised design solutions for packaging and promotion
- Developed visual assets and guidelines through campaigns
- Developed market strategies using 3D modelling and posters
- Collaborated with market teams to ensure brand adherence

GRAPHIC DESIGNER

- Created social media and print assets for a diverse audience
- Composed motion graphics video for promotion of Taekwondo and self defence in rural areas
- Initiated spiritual campaigns, with a 6% participation increase

GRAPHIC DESIGNER

- Devised digital marketing strategies
- Personalised forms of advertising lead to 10% increase in customer transactions
- · Created social media assets and met business goals

GRAPHIC DESIGNER

- · Created a brand identity and guidelines for global artists' fair
- Made posters, animations and GIFs, promoting in-house artists
- Directed multilingual media campaigns for French studies
- Revamped the website, creating UI and web design assets

DESIGN VOLUNTEER

- Faciliatated team meeting for market strategy and presented to stakeholders
- Collaborate with design and development teams
- Engaged in client feedback and showcased design concepts

EDUCATION

(2018 - 2021)

BA (Hons) Graphic Design

Middlesex University London, UK

(2016 - 2017)

Diploma in Design Communication

Lasalle College of the Arts Singapore, SG

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Adobe Creative Cloud

Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Lightroom, After Effects, Premiere Pro, Dimension, Acrobat and XD

Additional

Wacom Intuous (Digital illustrations)
Cinema 4D (beginner)
Sketch

AREA OF EXPERTISE

Graphic Design essentials

- Branding, brand settings, guidelines and identity design
- Typography, color theory and vector graphics
- Art direction and composition
- Layout and editorial design (web, digital, print)
- Photography (product shoots and studio lighting)
- Content generation and social media engagement

Additional

- Storyboarding
- Video scripts editing, motion design and animation (basic)
- 3D design, spatial and modeling
- Data analysis and infographics generation

CERTIFICATES AND ACTIVITES

(2023)

Neuro-Linguistic Programming (NLP) course

(2021 - 2022)

Social Work for ashram

(2014 - 2016)

Creative Cloud: Photoshop, Illustrator and Indesign course